### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/

### Top Skills

С

Embedded Systems VHDL

### Honors-Awards

Honorary prize for the best thesis issued by the federal minister of education, science and research

Kapsch Award 2016

Scholarship of Excellence 2015 Scholarship of Excellence 2014 Anniversary Study Abroad Scholarship

# **Gurpreet Krage**

Electronics | Embedded Systems | ASIC + FPGA | AMS Verification | Digital Design & Verification | Unmanned Aerial Systems Austria

### Summary

Experienced Developer and Lecturer with a demonstrated history of working in research, automotive and aerospace sectors. Skilled in Digital Design, Digital Verification, AMS/DMS Verification, Lab Validation, Jenkins, , SystemVerilog, VHDL, C, Python, Bash, TCL, Uvm, Embedded Software, Cadence, Questasim, Vivado, Quartus, Functional Coverage, Verification Architecture, Java, OOP, Linux, PCB Design, SoC FPGA Design, Strong engineering professional with a Master of Science (M.Sc.) focused in Embedded Systems.

## Experience

Photeon Technologies GmbH Design Engineer 2021 - Present (3 years) Austria

Fachhochschule Technikum Wien Lecturer Embedded Design November 2020 - February 2022 (1 year 4 months)

Courses on:

Embedded Programming (Programming Basics, Algorithms, Git, Software Testing, Build-Systems, Development Processes, Agile, Linux)
Embedded Software Engineering (µController, RTOS, wireless communication)

Elektrobit (EB)

Senior Digital Design Verification Engineer 2018 - February 2022 (4 years)

Working on FPGA Designs and their Verification on different Levels.

Requirements, Design Verification Plans, Testplans, Testbench Architecture & Implementation, Automated Regression Tests, Devops, CI/CD Infrastructure, Questasim, SystemVerilog, constrained randomization, functional

requirements, TLM, TCL, Python, Bash, UVM, Jenkins, Git, Linux, Ethernet, Bus Systems.

**UAS Technikum Wien** 

4 years

Research Associate

2014 - 2016 (2 years)

Josef Ressel Center for Verification of Embedded Computing Systems

Digital Design, Verification

Laboratory Technician (Embedded Systems)

2012 - 2014 (2 years)

UAS Technikum Wien, Vienna

Research Associate

2012 - 2012 (less than a year)

AC Centrope II (E-mobility)

Embedded Engineering, Bus Systems

NASA Ames Research Center

Visiting Scientist - Intelligent Systems Division

June 2014 - October 2014 (5 months)

Bachmann electronic GmbH

R&D Systemsoftware (Intern)

2010 - 2010 (less than a year)

BITS - Better IT Solutions GmbH

Software-/Database Development

2001 - 2009 (8 years)

## Education

Technische Universität Wien

PhD Student, Cyber Physical Systems Group · (2016)

UAS Technikum Wien, Vienna [AT]

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Embedded Systems · (2013 - 2015)

UAS Technikum Wien, Vienna [AT]

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Electronic Engineering · (2009 - 2013)

University of Technology, Sydney Electronic Engineering · (2012 - 2012)

Fudan University

Modern China Studies for Scientists and Economists · (2010 - 2010)